[Music]
Hey everyone, glad to be here. Dez, how
are you doing? Good. Yourself? I'm doing
great. I'm doing great. If you don't
mind, I'd love to embarrass you and give
a little bit more of an introduction
just for folks who may not be tracking
you uh super closely. Dez is I'm also
laughing at the difference in in the
photo you presented in the state of me
today. I would have shaved you. Sorry.
We'll update it for sure.
So Dez is the co-founder and chief
strategy officer of Intercom. And as
Dion was mentioning, Intercom helped
define modern inapp chat and is now
redefining what AI first customer
support can look like. And under Des's
leadership, uh, Intercom was one of the
first to fully commit to an autonomous
AI agent. It's part of what we're going
to be talking about in a few minutes.
And they've been pushing what's possible
for an agent in production. Also want to
point out that Dez is an active angel
investor. Dez, I think everybody says
that, but his portfolio includes
companies like Stripe, Miro, and Notion.
So, the real deal on that side as well.
And he's a leading voice in all things
product, startups, and the future of AI
powered software. So, uh, sorry to
embarrass you, Dez, but, uh, with that,
um, we're going to unpack this real
experience of what it's like to use AI
to build and scale an autonomous AI
agent and, uh, then we're going to have
a conversation about what it means for,
uh, software teams and for coding and
and for the industry more broadly. So,
let's dive in. Dez, you you've talked a
bunch about just the shift that you went
through from an initial prototype that
you did really early to scaling this
thing into production. And I wonder just
to kick things off if you could just
share what you learned about that
journey from an impressive boardroom
demo to actually using this for real.
Yeah. Um the like the biggest thing we
learned is uh AI building product in the
age of AI is extremely different. That's
like that's it in a nutshell and I'll
unpack that now. Um so we we had many
different impressive demos of Finn uh
which is our AI agent for customer
support. Um the problem with most of
them you know the story goes something
like chat launches November 30th. By
December we had versions of AI features
in our inbox. We were the first people
to basically build uh OpenAI uh GPT
features into our product. Wow. We had
the first prototypes of Finn in January
but this was on GPT 3.5. we couldn't
kind of safeguard against
hallucinations. So, what we could do at
the time was give you a really
impressive demo as long as we could
control what you said, you know. Um, and
it looked great and performed well as
long as you didn't put it into
production. And, uh, and I think for
what's I think there are still many u
many AI companies figuring this out. I
was going to say it sounds familiar.
Yeah. Yeah. Um, it was really when GP4
dropped was the beginning of like, oh,
well, we can actually control this. Uh,
we can like we were able to safeguard.
We have like this uh pretty robust
torture test of all the things you don't
want a customer support agent to do. You
don't want it to give the wrong answer.
You don't want it to make up an answer.
You don't want it to take an opinion
that it shouldn't take whether it's
political or about the world. You don't
want it to recommend your competitors.
You like there's so many things you
would never allow a human to do before
we even get into like the finetuning of
like let it let it speak in my brand ton
of voice. Like they're all kind of nice
to have. But it was really only when
four dropped which was March that we
were able to release a fully autonomous
agent that actually you could put in
front of your support team. And that was
like um the best thing I could say that
we learned was like AI product is just
fundamentally different in that you know
the the average software development
life cycle goes something like you know
talk to customers bit of research go off
into the forest wireframe some stuff up
come back start building you know run a
beta test ship it we're good and if it's
used even better and the AI software
development life cycle is a lot more
like brainstorm about all the things
that might be possible try see if you
can get it working in like in a sort of
internal pilot, then commit to building
it. Build it for real. Hope to god it
works in the wild. Once it's live, you
have to test the hell out of it anyway
because like, you know, we have like
30,000 customers, so if there's edges or
wrinkles in Finn, they're going to find
it. Um, and uh, and then you kind of are
in after that, you're in this like
constant process of iteration. So like
when we launched Finn, it I think it was
resolving maybe 25% of our customers
support conversations. Today it's doing
about 58 59%. Um that's been an entire
process of improving Finn behind the
scenes based on what we see in the wild.
And uh so it's like every single thing
you assume about software is usually
would have hinged on this idea of
working in time boxed or scope boxed
chunks. It's all out the window.
Everything is different in AI. Well,
first of all, Dez, I'd love to see the
torture test. I imagine that's not
something you make public, but oh my
god, it sounds, you know, like we we
don't, but you know, you could imagine,
you know, um it's like if you're trying
to do yourself, like let's say you're
trying to do one for Tesla or for any of
your customers, I would say to you like,
you know, there are like three or four
categories of things like show me the
last 20 hard questions that your
frontline support couldn't answer.
They'll go in. Show me the 10 most
common questions. They'll go in. Then
let's talk about like uh security
conscious like you know like as in you
don't want to get prompt injected or
anything like that. So you'll have a set
for that. And then you're into like
where you know what happens with a sales
conversation. Do you want your customer
support like leaning in or leaning out?
What uh what happens with something that
isn't answered in the docs but is nearly
answered in the docks. So you have to
kind of make it there's only a few of
these you should make up but you can
actually you can pretty I mean we
encourage our customers to do this all
the time because they say oh we want to
evaluate you and a load of agents. And
we're like okay that's cool. But the the
fallacy or the the worst evaluation we
ever see is I asked you and I asked
Zenesk uh how to reset my password and
you both got it right. And I'm like
cool. That's like asking me and Einstein
what's 2 plus two and then including
we're both great math. You know the
actual differences show on the edge. You
like we earn our money in the hard cases
not the easy cases. So I would say to
anyone and this is true for all of you
not even if you're buying CS agents but
actually as you're trying to demonstrate
superiority in agents uh you have to
like be able to teach your customers how
to understand the difference.
So sort of related to this clearly the
torture test plays a really big role in
in deciding whether a particular
iteration of FIN is ready for prime
time. What are sort of the other
indications that u you've achieved
production readiness in a probabilistic
environment? Like how do you quantify
this? How do you get to the point where
you feel like this thing's ready?
Yeah, there's two other sort of product
markety fit type things. One is is like
um it's a very obvious one, but just
like some sense of does anyone give a
So like uh so in the case of of
like Finn answering questions, of
course, everyone cares and if it does a
good job, that's great. The um it's more
all the stuff we build around the edges
of Finn. So we build a whole test suite
where you can like have a you know do
batch testing or like do deep testing of
specific scenarios or you know we're
about to launch a very very cool new
product next uh next Wednesday um which
is all around analysis of your customer
support conversations but you are
looking for two things with these types
of releases that are non like where
where the answer isn't that percentage
goes up. You're looking for frequent
engagement and and like meaningful
outcomes. So a lot of what we build is
like uh is it's supposed to help people
get the most out of our product. Uh so
what we look at is do they use it a lot
and then uh I if they do does it
actually change their behavior
ultimately Finn is about getting you to
like 100% AI resolutions or as close as
we don't really believe you're going to
get to 100 but um if so like what we
look to do is like hey since we released
that has behavior gotten better or
worse. So that that's one thing and the
reason I that sounds like I mean that
probably is some abstract level true for
all software but just the mindset shift
you have to have when you're building an
agent is that you're trying to build
something to do a job completely. So
then you have to build all the
peripheral software that helps you
manage the agent or helps your customers
manage that agent so that they can get
it to do the job completely and so that
they can actually score it and say it's
doing a good job or a bad job. Would
they hire it or fire it? Would it get a
promotion? Would it be on a pip? you
kind of have to equip your customers to
understand all that. Um the other thing
I'd say is um agent behavior like
basically uh you can imagine in the wild
world of support uh you have like the
Four Seasons has a different customer
support policy to say like um EasyJet or
Riner or Southwest depending your budget
airline wherever you live right like
some um and like basically different
brands have different uh basically
different LTVs of their customers or
they value their customers in different
ways. So every time you bump into one of
these um sort of vectors of
differentiation within your within your
sort of customer set, you then have to
create effectively preferences or
settings for how the agent should
behave. Now a common thing people do is
they say, "Oh, that's okay. We're just
going to have one big ass prompt box and
they can just write in everything they
want." And that sounds really good, but
it's impossible to maintain. Your
customers are not prompt engineers.
There's a right way to tell somebody to
be a be quick and efficient and there's
a bad way to do it. And like, you know,
if you expose like a kind of raw prompt
to all your customers all the time,
you'll get some bad behavior. Like it's
it's um every time you're giving your
customer a large text area and saying
and saying some version of describe the
behavior you want, you're kind of
handing them a very sharp knife and
crossing your fingers a little bit. So,
so you you end up having to distill
these things down into sort of you
ultimately you end up designing the
feature not just being like you know all
cars you tell us what you want. Uh this
is it's almost like the the Henry Ford
thing. It's just slightly different.
Customers want different things. It's
your job to like identify the common
traits of those things. So to give you
one simple example in Finn, we special
case things like tone of voice and we
special case things like answer length
because there's a right way to tell
Claude or to tell Finn, hey, here's the
the length of answer we want and there's
a stupid way and so you could say be
really short and what you'll get is a
very rude agent. Uh so so you have to
like kind of help your customers but I I
do notice there's a tendency with
startups to say you can you know here's
a big text box you know go nuts and
customers do go nuts and then they think
your product sucks. So yeah that's the
other aspect is just make sure that
you've you've kind of paved the common
desire paths of behavior so that the
customers don't have to work it all out
themselves. And how does that I haven't
been on the other side of your product.
How does that manifest? Is it like
documentation you give your customers or
is the customization UI sort of set up
so that they can't get off the happy
path? How do you how do you do that?
It's the latter. So like so we do you
know it we uh we just give you like
literal you know buttons that say like
you know what tone of voice do you want
or whatever and we recommend like you
can we have a feature called guidance
where you can add in your like your
extra stuff on top. An example would be
like maybe like Airbnb wants to refer to
their guests as like patrons and maybe
they want to refer to the landlords a
certain way like you know there's things
like that but the way in which we've
built Finn that's
um it's important where you apply that
to the answer you should generate the
answer first and then and then follow
the guidance to adapt the answer to meet
the say like the requirements of words
or verbiage or whatever. However, if you
kind of like let it go in raw you'll
you'll set yourself up in a bad way. So
ultimately what Finn is is we know all
the common things that companies differ
on and we give you all the options and
preferences you need for that and then
there's an after the fact sort of now if
you've any weird special rules like
maybe you call yourselves test or
something like that we'll deal with
that. Yeah. Brilliant. Exactly. We'll
deal with that after once we've
generated a nice conure concise answer
that's humorous and happy and it
references these materials and that once
we've got all that done then let's apply
your frankly like slightly less
important stuff. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
I had this existential moment as
listening to you where we were talking
about how do you sort of coax the LLMs
to do just the right thing and then we
shifted to how do you coax humans to do
just the right thing. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
You know, it's funny that that
conversation comes up a lot like uh I
was discussing the so we have this
feature called tasks where you can
basically tell Finn, hey, here's how we
do a refund. Uh and you you know people
measure it. Um you know, we we care a
lot about the reliability of these steps
in a task because like if something's
only 90% reliable and you daisy chain
three of those steps in a row, you're
down to like nonperformance thing. Yeah.
The sort of probability gap or whatever
compound. Um, what's interesting is
you're like, you know, I had a customer
say, "How do you get like these like
slightly ineffective or slightly
inefficient things to like work together
still deliver a required outcome?" And I
was like, "Have you ever been a
manager?" That's literally what it is.
Like, you know, Johnny's hung over,
Debbie didn't show up. We still need the
system to work. You know, like it's you
like the nature of companies is they are
ways to get these slightly unreliable
agents to do things predictably and
deliver some sort of common consistent
service to the world, you know.
Well, um I think this is interesting
time to talk about more of the
interaction between the agent and
humans. Let's sort of start out with you
talked about the success rate getting
now I think to 58 59% which is for those
keeping track I think is like a 10%
boost since the last time we talked uh
some time ago like nine months ago or
whatever. Um how do you what are the
signals you look for when it's clear
that you have to engage a human in the
conversation? Do you just sort of like
when I when I deal with some online
service providers, I won't mention
names. I feel like I have to type agent
agent agent.
Yeah. How do you do it? I mean like you
know the the shortest answer is we
actually ask you hey did this answer
your question and so like that's the
most obvious. If somebody says anything
other than like a positive answer then
that's an obvious route to agent and we
look for frustration. We look for uh
like as in frustration might emerge in
the middle of a conversation where we
think we're having a back and forth but
the person is either you know caps
locking it or whatever. Um, there's also
like in the guidance feature I mentioned
earlier, you can have like escalation
settings like you know if they mention
scam or or like hacked or whatever,
always escalate. If if it sounds like
the user's being compromised, if it
sounds like they're worried, if it
sounds like, you know, you've all sorts
of like every type of business has a
specific hot button concern. Like if
you're an online gaming company, you
care a lot about people who, you know,
say they're feeling very down after a
certain bad beat or something like that.
So you kind of you have to kind of
special case every one of these um with
with the guidance feature. But we
generally look for like uh anything that
suggests that the user even if the user
just starts a new conversation straight
away that's a that's another negative
sign. Um anything that looks basically
like wasn't a positive conclusion uh
would be like a would be the beginning
of a path to escalate. But but to be
clear our default wouldn't be to
immediately hand over to human because
that's not again that's not what
customers want or what our customers
want. What it will be is to ask, "Do you
want to talk to a human?" And then
you'll say yes and then you'll get over
because sometimes people will just go
silent while they're clicking around the
screen and you don't want to be like,
"All right, here's John. He's going to
solve your problem." Like they're
actually halfway through whatever answer
you gives them. So, and I imagine
different customers of yours have
different thresholds for how much they
might be willing to sort of I don't want
to say antagonize, but sort of wait
until they do the escalation to the
human. Absolutely. And they have
different like they're kind of like
different everything honestly. customer.
I think customer service a lot of folks
don't um don't respect it enough for how
nuanced it is as a domain. I think um
it's one of these situations where if
you work in one customer support or that
might have like clean and simple rules,
you might therefore be uh misled into
thinking that it's therefore a clean and
simple problem domain. But in practice,
what it is is this extremely large
supererset of like you know probably
hundreds of company preferences. uh and
you have to kind of like work out a way
sort of happy path through all of them
in your product offering. So yes,
thresholds for when we should hand over,
what we should hand over, how we should
hand over, the delay before handing
over, do you hand over to a live agent
or do you hand over to an asynchronous
follow-up? Would you do you want to hand
over to request a fallback, you know, or
sorry, a call back? Like all of those
things are like in the mix here. And
it's yeah, you're you're kind of waiting
through a sea of preferences. H talking
about sort of the interaction between um
humans and the agent a little more. Um I
imagine the stuff that gets routed to
humans becomes more and more the edge
cases becomes more and more complicated.
How does what does the shift do for job
satisfaction of of the humans involved?
Do they do they tend to like their jobs
more or does it start to feel like kind
of an assembly line grind where you only
get like the grubby stuff that that is
really no fun? I think it it depends on
on a it's kind of an issue of
perspective. So I think what happens a
lot is um there's a few things people
don't realize about customer service.
One is uh it's a very transitional job
because it's primarily entry level. So
when you are thinking of a customer
support agent you should realize that
almost by definition that person is
either just after starting the job or is
just about to leave the job. That's like
it was my first job coming into industry
way back when like and that's a very
common story. um like the amount of CEOs
of our customers who say that they got
their first start in CS or whatever. Um
so it is like there's a there's um
there's a tendency to be like no no
preserve those jobs and it's kind of
like that age-old argument of like if we
in if we force the construction
companies to build to dig with spoons
we'd have more jobs you know but it
wouldn't be good jobs like you know
there's a reason why we invent
technology and we try to move faster and
better. So I think what we see is in
practice when when you apply Finn and
you get the 56% reduction a few things
happen like your first response time
which is a classic CS metric that goes
way faster because obviously Finn's very
fast but then your agents are less
burdened as well so they get a lot
faster. Your average handling time which
is a previous uh sort of measure again
an incumbent measure that goes way up
because your humans are only dealing
with really hard stuff now. They're only
dealing with the stuff that like wasn't
in any way answered by any documents
anywhere. So the complexity goes up and
ultimately what you see the changes you
see happen in a customer support org is
there is sometimes it will either stays
like uh relative to the support volume
it will get smaller right uh or
sometimes it actually shrinks itself but
certainly like what you see a lot of the
time is they stop growing uh the next
change you see is there's a lot more
specialization so you get like you know
principal product specialist on a
support team and that like role is you
know usually higher paid, usually higher
valued, there's a lot more expertise and
all of a sudden what happens is a career
path emerges for customer support people
where they can actually like use the
fact that they've worked in this company
for like three, four, five years. They
really understand the product inside and
out. They know all the edge cases and
now they can get paid for that because
they're not spending half their day
explaining how to reset passwords.
They're actually putting all their time
into like really high quality like
ultimately quite differentiated work. So
that's the change. The other side of it
is um what we call like human in the
loop. So the new kind of frontline uh
support might be a bit more human
approval processes that can be a bit
gruntier or grindy like as you said like
in that like um a classic step would be
like approve this refund before it goes
live and the approval is I just want a
human to eyeball this to make sure that
they haven't in some way exploited the
bot or whatever right and uh and so that
would usually look like a human going
yep the order yes it's late and yes
that's that. Okay, click. And uh and
that work again, it's it's like not, you
know, it's it's there because there's a
degree of trust or human validation that
the the business wants to enforce and
that will ultimately just be a cue or an
inbox that you're just jumping through.
I suspect over time people will find
better ways to grow more trust and
confidence in agents to handle that. But
that's like when you look at the sort of
topology of a support team, you get a
lot more specialists, a lot uh frankly
fancier job titles like AI and then you
get people who own the agent and own the
intelligence because all these other
changes happen like um your
documentation is now like mission
critical infrastructure because it's
literally how your support works. Yeah.
So, so all of a sudden you really care
about that being really good and really
reliable and really up to date and it's
worth investing in it. Um, you've got
people who own the automations for
things like refunds or flight changes or
baggage routes or whatever like whatever
your business is you you have to have
somebody who's in charge of Finn if you
like. So I I think a lot of things
change but the like there's definitely
an optimistic take here which is like
the like you know if you've ever seen
like you mean you mentioned you started
it if you ever seen where these kind of
like uh call centers look like or where
these live chat centers look like it is
not the job that like we you know
there's a kind of a temptation like oh
no protect them and keep them in their
factories they'll be happy there. I
think that's the wrong way to think
about it. I think what you know another
way another argument is offer a really
good career path from this and yeah
maybe there's less total roles but like
if you look at humanity's employment
over time we've always found stuff to do
like I think I was joking with somebody
recently where they were saying like you
know like think about what the
spreadsheet did to investment banking
right one of my friends used to joke you
know investment bankers used to be
really busy before the spreadsheet got
invented and I'm like right and it's not
you know they're obviously still quite
busy now um the spreadsheet like the big
fear of the spreadsheet was it would
kill all bookkeepers and in practice
when you look at the numbers it is true
that there are less bookkeepers per
business now than there used to be but
are there less people employed no
accountancy kicked off all these other
like uh analysts financial analysts
kicked off all these other sectors
emerged there were like you know higher
order higher value and I think that's
the sort of thing you're going to see
happen uh so it's not really just about
a net loss in jobs to my mind it's about
like you know there there is
displacement I don't want to lie about
that like you know I can't be sitting
here saying we're doing 56% and also
there's change. There will be some
changes, but uh I think there'll be, you
know, in a load of cases remarkably
positive changes. Does it am I am I
right to maybe even fantasize a little
bit about new kind of high lever jobs of
the future where you have support
agents, humans who are kind of looking
at what the agents are doing and sort of
planning strategy and seeing new
patterns emerge and sort of
strategically engaging to sort of
control this fleet of agents. I mean,
that seems like a really cool job. Well,
and and like that's coming like as in um
I wasn't going to like try and pitch on
anything, but like tomorrow week in
London, we're literally having an event
where we're launching the f first
product in that line of thinking where
you have a kind of a dashboard for
seeing what's going on. And based on
that, you can then make decisions about
what else do I need to tell Finn, how
can I equip Finn, etc. Can't say too
much about it because we haven't
launched yet, but uh but like this is
not actually a clumsy sort of like pitch
moment. This is like totally organic.
This is so cool, man. Yeah. It's like
but you know I think there is an
interesting thread we've been pulling
that a lot of your guests or so your
your viewers might be interested in
which is it's one thing to like identify
a job whether it's like you know a coder
whether it's marketing copy whether it's
an SDR whether it's customer support the
next thing you have to do is build all
the surrounding tooling for the person
whose job it is to set that up so like
you know uh just just to make this not a
pitch let's just say if we take
something like sales representative like
person who does sales live chat
If you nail that with an agent, that can
really be a really persuasive uh sort of
uh chat with a website visitor to sell
them on a product, that's cool. The
first thing your customers are going to
ask is, "Is this working? How do I make
it better? How do I improve it? How do I
see what's going on so I can get better
answers?" And all of a sudden, you have
to build this like agent operating
platform, which is like your kind of
like your your heads up display for what
the hell's going on. Yeah. if you you
know and I so like there are all these
like uh peripheral tools that go around
the agent which is by the way as a side
note is why it kills me whenever anyone
gets into the discussion about thin
rappers or any of that. I'm just like
you don't realize how much software you
have to build to like handle 50 60 70%
of a support of the support of a large
company you know. Yeah totally man. Um
so looking at time I think we have
another 12 minutes or so before the end
of the session. So if any of you have
questions to ask go ahead and just enter
the questions. We've got a team
monitoring and I'll interrupt the
conversation to take your question and
Dez will answer it. In the meantime, I'm
just going to keep jamming with Dez and
uh and we'll keep going. Um so I I want
to pivot a little bit uh because in
addition to the product you're building,
but I can't wait to see what you
announce. That sounds amazing. Um I just
wonder if you could give us some
insights on how you use AI codegen tools
at Intercom. like uh are you using like
tools like bolt and replet and lovable
and and and vzero and the like or or do
you just sort of stick with sort of more
sort of autocomplete type stuff? What is
your stack and and what learnings do you
have to share? So um we're about 500
people in R&D maybe 100 in marketing.
That's the areas where I know we we have
deployed AI mostly. Um all of our
engineers uh by default are like wind or
like cursor or wind surf. On top of
that, we've layered on uh clawed code is
another common one. I think a lot of our
AI group use that. And then um and then
like for um what what to me like all of
that is is like perhaps slightly closer
to the autocompletes. Um what I would
say is most interesting for me is is
things like say lovable as an
alternative to Figma. Uh so as an
example very related to the feature I
just described um data visualization is
extremely annoying to build out in Figma
or any sort of design tool. Yeah. Uh
like if you want to build like dynamic
uh adaptive like hey understand these 25
conversations and plot sentiment on a
bar chart or blah blah it's extremely
wasteful to have like designers dragging
and dropping various sized rectangles in
a row or any version of that. Right? And
it's actually quite rewarding to um to
think about lovable or or any of any of
the equivalents create or v whatever. If
you think about them more as a
wireframing tool than a final product
tool in this exact case for a second,
you can get really far by saying right
we need to design a a data visualization
for a certain type of product or for a
certain you know like how would you
visualize all of the most common topics
and what the most frequent questions in
those topics are. How would you
visualize that? And you might say, "Oh,
we could do it with like a tide cloud or
a bubble diagram or we could do like
just a tree map or like there are like
loads of different ones now, right? Like
in, you know, we go back to 2021 or 2022
before chat drops. What actually happens
there is people either start sketching
or whiteboarding or they waste a lot of
time dragging squares and circles around
in a uh in a browser to try and
visualize these ideas. we can now kind
of explore the solution space for all
possible
visualizations. Realistically, in like
maybe two hours of just prompting,
right? Two hours of good prompting will
get you like 10 or 12 different ideas
that you can then look at and flick
through and be like, which one of these
makes sense. You can even feed it real
data and uh and it, you know, because
it'll work because it's actually live
code. It's not like a perfectly dragged
square. And um and you can look at these
things and be like, "Huh, I think item
number four is up." And you can kind of
pull a thread on that. Well, let's add
some drop downs. What pickers would we
need? How what filters would we need?
And you're doing all this. These are all
design things. You're doing it in like a
proper prototyping tool uh in Figma.
Sorry, not in Figma. Although Figma as
of last week's releases might be
relevant here. Um but like certainly
vzero both whatever. And you can kind of
like I often say explore the solution
space which is like try out 10 different
things and then exploit. So then you
when you've picked your your version,
you can then move into a different type
of prompting which is extremely deep
refinement which is where you can get to
apply like you know either like specific
UI constraints or like uh art direction
for the aesthetics or whatever and you
can get it a lot closer. You can give it
all like the um the elements of your own
UI like here here's the typography we
use here's our icon set and all it will
work all that out as well and then you
can actually look at something that's a
lot closer. Again, before we've asked an
engineer to write a line of code, we can
then be looking at something that's way
closer. That's something you can then
sit with an engineer and like you've
you've kind of saved what could have
honestly in the olden days been, you
know, weeks if not months of like
various different explorations and
workshopping. You've reduced it to like
a day, two days, three days sort of
thing. And uh and that's probably for my
mind the single most impactful change
that you should see in your software
development life cycle when you're
properly AI enabled is the ability to
explore and exploit should shrink from
like weeks to like hours. And if you do
that right because like I think you know
we we I often hear engineers say this
like like writing code as in like the
fingers on keyboard piece is not the
hard part. The hard part is you start
building one thing and the designer
changes their mind and the PM says,
"Nope, sorry. That feature has to go
in." And then if you had known that, you
would have built it a different way.
Like the the whole process can be quite
messy, but you can figure out so much
extra in advance if you do proper
prototyping.
Thank you for that. Um I want to come
back to that with uh a question, but
first I want to get to Martin Bishop's
question. So Martin Bishop, thanks for
your question. He asks, "How much impact
do you see when you change the
underlying models?"
So I would say of the like 25 to 50% 57%
or whatever whatever today's figure is I
I I think like honestly only like two or
3% of that is attributable to like
various different models like uh it's
not massive. Uh we part we went we
partnered with anthropic because we
believe they have the we have the best
partnership with them and they had the
best models as per our torture test. But
um I think uh Finn is like not a it's
not like a singleshot agent. It's a
subsystem of about 15 different uh
processes. There's like a process for
disambiguating. There's a process, you
know, there's like obviously chucking,
reranking, uh summarizing. Then there's
like the actual the the heart of film.
When you've sourced all, you've
performed your rag, you've done all of
that. At the very heart is then this
idea of answer this question. Um I think
we like we have experimented with say
open source ones. We've experimented
with deepseek etc. we like they're all
slightly worse than our current setup.
That's the result of doing like hundreds
of AB tests to perfect our current
setup. But I think um the a the agent
like say the the actual model itself is
not as high a unit of leverage versus
the actual say the agent architecture.
That's a thing that we saw a lot of win
in. So we're I think we're on our third
major architecture of Finn at this
point. every one of them has been
significant in terms of improvement uh
to like the resolution rate. Prompts
probably second. Um and then there's
other like slightly peripheral things
that aren't the pure AI stuff like so um
um our rag engines is bespoke. Our
ranker is bespoke. These are all things
that we've actually perfected
specifically for what we do. Some of
this is because we happened to have uh
we had a previous AI product. So we had
a lot of these things ready to go
already pretty tuned. And of course back
in the old days you really had to tune
them because the performance was so
tough to get. So uh so yeah I think I'd
say like you know a lot of people think
like hey like Deepseek dropped why isn't
Finn going up or whatever and we're like
well because that's not where the meat
of the problem is. You know I I'm I'm
imagining like you've sort of built a
proprietary vertically specific
reasoning model on top of whatever
underlying LLM you have and because of
that like all these other things are
just very very incremental to the
reasoning you've built in. Yeah. And
that's not to say that they're um
insignificant like we we fight for every
one of these percent if you know what I
mean. Yeah. But yeah, but but you are
correct. Yeah. Interesting. So uh next
question. Uh Radica asks, "Could AI
coding tools be useful for less
experienced developers to write more
efficient and scalable code?" That's an
interesting one. Yeah, I I can't say
this for sure. I can just give my
opinion.
Um I think the degree to which you can
you know you're like one area I think a
lot of teams don't spend enough time in
is um like before you know AI happened
we already had an R&D operations team
and one of the things they spent a lot
of time optimizing was our developer
environment uh so we care a lot about
this and we had a team who focused on
this already. Uh I think when AI
happened a thing a lot of companies do
is just like hey like you know someone
posts on Slack hey you should all go and
check out cursor anyway back to work and
I think if you really want to get
results you need to kind of take a
stronger opinion. So that looks like
things like uh writing your you know
your as Jean who was on the previous
speaker was saying like write your rules
file or your claw.md or whatever like
explain exactly the type of code you
want to some degree it's also a function
of is is your existing codebase uh
coherent like you know high cohesion low
coupling blah blah blah like is it easy
could you know but um so I I would posit
to Radica's question like I my suspicion
is if your codebase is pretty easy to
learn and pretty easy to work with. What
you'll find is uh like AI coding tools
will be great for uh accelerating a new
person's ability to contribute. Um if
your codebase is let's just say older,
contains multiple different versions,
has lots of different like uh libraries,
you know, if you're mixing all sorts of
various generations of of of software
together, then the chances are no is my
experience. And I think um the challenge
then becomes like uh do you should you
consider like you know ultimately like
rewriting parts of your product like the
core engines where you need to do most
of your improvement. Should you think
about rewriting from a point of view
getting them into shape so that the AI
tools can help? That's the kind of a big
question for a lot of orgs that they're
facing right now. And it's worth asking
even though no one likes to say the
rewrite word, but you have to bear in
mind like your competitors who were
started in the last six months, who were
like born in some YC garage somewhere,
they have none of your tech debt.
They've none of your legacy
They're going to have the freedom to
build all this stuff like natively in AI
from the get-go. they so no matter you
might think it's an advantage that
you've got seven years of coding and a
seven year of like of of product work
behind you what they see is we're going
to take five screenshots feed it all to
claude and tell it to write it using the
latest and greatest and we'll have all
the features that you have now and we
got them in two weeks and the AI knows
how to improve them does your AI know
how to improve it and these are slightly
existential scary questions but I think
you have to kind of ask them to get
proper kind of like situ situational
awareness of what you're facing.
We have like a minute left and I see
this question. Let me just parse it for
a second. Uh
um Okay. Yeah, maybe we can do this in
like a minute or less. Dez, like h how
are customers receiving Finn? Like do
you see customers being concerned with
job loss and other things or or are
people embracing the cost savings with
open arms?
Um different categories. So we 5,000
customers or so. Uh revenue is in like
the tens of millions. It's growing very
fast. Uh we
um like the general response is it's
like it's a glass of ice water to
somebody in hell because a lot of
customer support teams are extremely
underwater. So the very second they turn
on Finn, they kind of get their breath
back and they can get through the
backlog and they're now finally their
heads above water. That was anthropic uh
experience when they started using it.
They that's the actual quote they gave
us. They're like it was the first time
we actually got down to inbox zero in
the customer support or So that's one
reaction and in those cases it's not
like they're not thinking oh great now
we can rightsize our support team.
They're thinking finally we've got we
can start we can kind of get a handle on
things. So that's a very genuine
reaction. Uh sometimes if there's like a
BO a business process outsource firm
involved their contract might not get
renewed on the far side of all this.
That's just natural like they were
brought in and it's a temporary thing.
They're they leave as a temporary thing.
In terms of our customers, customers,
some of the funniest reactions we see
are things like like, you know, human
takes over the conversation and we'll
see somebody say, "Sorry, I was actually
doing Grand with Finn. Could you put me
back to Finn, please?" And it's not it's
not that Finn's brilliant so much as
this, they don't like the idea that
they're bothering a human. They, you
know, it would be like as if if you knew
there was a human behind chatbt doing
all the lookups based on what you said.
You'd feel a lot more sympathy and be
like, "You know what? I don't need to
bother you anymore." So, there's a thing
where people like the idea there's a bot
there to answer every question that they
might otherwise have to look up, you
know. Yeah, absolutely. Dez, you've been
so generous with your time. You stayed
up late. You're here local and and
European time, UK time. Thank you so
much for your time. This has been a
really fun conversation for me. I
enjoyed it too, Ben. Thanks a lot. And
thanks to everyone else who came along.
Baker.